<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on /vishnuvp</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on /vishnuvp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>© vishnuvp {year}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 13:09:08 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Access Host From Docker Container in Macos</title><link>/blog/access-host-from-docker-container-in-macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 13:09:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blog/access-host-from-docker-container-in-macos/</guid><description>If you are running a docker container and if you need to access a service running on the host for testing, the option in Ubuntu and other linux distros is to use the docker0 interface. This will not work in MacOS as Docker-Desktop-for-Mac networking is programmed different.
To make this scenario work, Docker Desktop for Mac provides a work around and it is pretty simple. The gateway is provided with an internal DNS name host.</description></item><item><title>Snowflake JSON Capabilities</title><link>/blog/snowflake-json-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 22:23:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blog/snowflake-json-capabilities/</guid><description>Snowflake is a relational DBMS. However, it supports querying and manipulating JSON data by providing a special data type called Variant. So, if we store the JSON documents in a single column table, Snowflake will effectively be querying JSON object.
For example, consider this table defenition:
CREATE TABLE JSON_DATA (DATA VARIANT); If the JSON documents are in an S3 bucket, we can import the data using a copy into command.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Data Ingestion in Snowflake Using Snowpipe</title><link>/blog/automatic-data-ingestion-in-snowflake-using-snowpipe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 15:52:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blog/automatic-data-ingestion-in-snowflake-using-snowpipe/</guid><description>Snowflake is the new buzzword in the cloud world, which offers data-warehouse-as-a-service (probably DWAAS in the cloud lingo). If you would like to read more about its capabilities and use cases around it, take a look at their site here. FYI, they have built a new SQL Engine from scratch, and the whole platform runs on AWS infrastructure. It is a technological irony that Snowflake performs better (in my opinion) than Amazon Redshift in many ways.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>/blog/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 18:55:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>/blog/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello ¡Hola! नमस्ते Bonjour! Здравствуйте! நமஸ்காரம் ನಮಸ್ಕಾರ! നമസ്‌കാരം
I learned that inertia is temporary. So, I have moved away from blogger. This is my new abode for rare to occasional technical blabberings and travelogues. The old blog is still up at vishnuvenukumar.blogspot.com - all posts intact; in case someone finds one of the random troubleshooter posts useful.
I will try to move older posts here, probably during the next vacation.</description></item></channel></rss>